# мг **MyName1**

Position: Oracle DBA

Availability: 1 month notice

Interview Availability: 72 hours notice

Salary Expectations: On £72k + OT & OCA - £75,000 base

Location: Essex

Eligibility: British

Holiday: 12<sup>th</sup> – 18<sup>th</sup> Feb

Contact: Neil McCreadie

**Number:** 07884 071 534 / 01273 355182

Email: <a href="mailto:neil.mccreadie@william-alexander.com">neil.mccreadie@william-alexander.com</a>



#### **PROFILE**

I am an enthusiastic, energetic about quality and highly determined Oracle Database Administrator (DBA) with over 16 years of experience working in designing, coding, testing and supporting next-generation database solutions in OLTP / Oracle Enterprise Server environments.

An extremely motivated Oracle Database Administrator with the ability to work effectively in team environments or independently using my own initiative. In addition, I have excellent communication and interpersonal skills, working well with customers and colleagues of all levels, as well as strong analytical and problem solving skills. I am customer focused with the ability to complete time-pressured business critical deliverables.

Proficient in an collection of technologies including Oracle 9i/10g/11g/12c, Oracle E-Business Suite, MS Access, MS SQL Server, JDBC, Microsoft Visio, SQL Developer, Toad, RMAN, ASM, OEM Grid Control, OEM Cloud Control, ITBM, GSMS, BMC Remedy, GoldenGate, Service Now, EMC Networker, GitLab, Trello, Dynatrace, pgAdmin, DBeaver, MySQL Workbench, PGP Encryption, Citrix, Solaris, Windows, Unix and Linux.

## **KNOWLEDGE, SKILLS AND ABILITIES:**

- Oracle 9i/10g/11g/12c Database Administration
- PostgreSQL, Replication, Administration
- MySQL Database Administration
- PostgreSQL/ MySQL management using pgAdmin, DBeaver and Workbench
- Oracle E-Business Suite, WebLogic Administration
- Performance Tuning & Capacity Monitoring
- Backup & Recovery RMAN / User Managed, Flashback, GRP
- Data Guard (Active/ Snapshot) Standby / Failover Administration
- · Database monitoring using shell scripting
- Oracle Enterprise Grid Control Monitoring
- Proactive maintenance & system monitoring
- Oracle RAC & ASM Administration/Installation, DBCA/DBUA/ASMCA
- Oracle Installation, tuning, patching, upgrades, migration
- Upgrading Oracle Database 9i / 10g to 11g / 12c
- Day-to-day Database Administration tasks
- LogMiner using manual method and OEM
- SQL Tuning in an Oracle Environment
- Working with Pre-Prod & Production deployment / code releases
- Production On-Call 24x7 Support
- Patch updates and general reporting
- Oracle Enterprise Manager Grid/Cloud Control 12c Upgrade
- Oracle Enterprise Manager Grid/Cloud Control 13c Upgrade
- Performance monitoring using OEM 12c / 13c
- Good communication and interpersonal skills
- AWR, ADDM, ASH, ADDM, Wait event, tkprof, Explain Plan, Statspack,
- SQL trace, SQL Profile, SQL Plan Baseline Management, SQL Health check
- Cloning, Backup & Recovery (RMAN, Data Pump, BMR, Tablespace)
- Transporting Tablespaces between Databases
- Excellent verbal and written communication skills.
- Good problem solving and design skills
- Able to work under pressure and to tight deadlines
- Accuracy & attention to detail
- Professional, well presented and possess an Agile mindset
- Establishes effective working relationships at all levels
- Demonstrable track record of understanding the business areas
- Strong Passion for customer service and best practice
- Team-player, flexible and able to work in a fast-paced environment
- Guiding agile project teams to achieve a high level of performance.



#### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Jun 2016 – Present Cancer Research UK, London, UK Senior Oracle Database Administrator

In this role I am responsible for the management and effective day to day running of the Oracle database environments. This includes ensuring the effective set-up, configuration, migration and upgrading of CRUK databases and platforms. This includes preparation for new or changed services, the maintenance of regulatory, legal and professional standards, and migration projects and services in relation to their contribution to business performance. I continually assess database performance to ensure problem areas are highlighted and mitigated. Act as a review function for all changes and updates made to production databases. Ensure all databases are patched in accordance with the internal security teams' recommendations, and in line with the patching policy. Act as an Oracle Subject Matter Expert (SME) during enhancement of production applications, including working with developers during their design, development and implementation activities.

### Key Duties:

- Configuring, troubleshooting, securing and maintaining the CR UK's database systems.
- Oracle Database administration Oracle 12c, 11g and 10g, working with server hardware and within a virtualised environment.
- Oracle Enterprise Manager 11g to Oracle Cloud Control 13c upgrade in Red Hat Enterprise Linux operating system.
- Backup management using EMC Networker, DataPump, SQL\*Loader, RMAN, MS SQL maintenance scheduling.
- Database monthly scheduling and maintenance.
- SQL Server windows monthly patching.
- Perform capacity planning across Oracle Database, Fusion Middleware, and Oracle Linux
- Apply patches and major releases across the Oracle Database install base.
- Manage changes to the environment using existing Change Management best practices and automation tools.
- Optimize IT operations using the latest tools and products from Oracle and the OpenSource community.
- Manage Oracle databases (memory structures, processes, storage structures, schemas etc).
- Administer users and security, profiles and customised limits.
- Housekeeping, documentation of all migration procedures & processes in SharePoint & internal Wiki.
- Reordering LONG column in an empty table and in a table containing data.
- PostgreSQL, Replication, Administration and MySQL Administration.
- PostgreSQL Database setup for Tibco and Replication setup.
- Automation, regular maintenance & scheduling tasks using shell scripting.
- Database cloning, patching, Shell scripts, creating scripts for tables & indexes, performance tuning.
- Perform performance tuning and optimization activities across Oracle Databases.
- Dynatrace database monitoring healthchecks and comparing to the infrastructure overview of hosts and processes.
- Provide best-practice recommendations across the database estate, and monitor subsequent implementations.

Mar 2007 – May 2016 Xchanging a CSC Company, Basildon, UK Senior Oracle Database Administrator

Daily activities and implementation works are undertaken in our challenging, fat-paced, dynamic environment where the time is managed effectively between production support and project work to meet delivery expectations of the customers. This is achieved by multi-tasking and prioritising workloads effectively where a large number of incidents/requests are handled for internal and external customers. Manage Oracle Database Administration assignments for diverse industry customers. Enhance database performance, perform restores, implement recovery procedures, DR tests, handle performance tuning and conduct regular system backups. Ensure technical and functional designs meet business requirements, project management, production acceptance and service coordination.

Key Duties:



- Served as DBA or project lead in the completion of 25+ medium to large-scale implementations, managing projects from business requirements analysis to solutions delivery and support.
- Oracle Enterprise Manager 10g to Oracle Cloud Control 12c upgrade in Oracle Solaris operating system.
- Oracle database installations, configuration, migrations, system upgrades, patching / install service packs to environments.
- Oracle 11g WebLogic Server Administration experience.
- Oracle E-Business Suite R12 Server Administration experience.
- Patching and upgrading development, test and production databases.
- Setting up Oracle Grid Control and initiating bespoke monitoring for target databases.
- Undertaking of backup and recovery of databases using RMAN and traditional user managed backups.
- Reviewing and implementing schema changes from test databases into production.
- Working with development to improve SQL performance.
- Creating processes for refreshing test databases to match the evolving production databases.
- Daily database administration, maintenance and performance monitoring.
- Setup Oracle GoldenGate to migrate/upgrade the critical databases to minimize the downtime.
- Special cloning, refresh requirements for customers (RMAN, Duplicate, Data Pump, User Managed backups).
- Oracle performance tuning, troubleshooting, (AWR/ ADDM) advanced Database Flashback activities.
- Capacity planning and Dashboard reporting activities.
- Oracle Enterprise Manager Grid control maintenance.
- Managing Oracle database and other Oracle product licenses.
- Log rotations, table management, archiving according to business requirements.
- DR and Business Continuity management of environments.
- DR testing and configuration.
- Support and maintained SQL Server databases.
- Production Acceptance Criteria (PAC) process, version control and processes documentations.
- Problem, incident, change management.
- Automation of various non-interactive and repetitive tasks and processes.
- Primary out-of-hours DBA On-Call support for the 24x7/365 Production systems.
- Solid experience of working in a global team, utilizing a "Follow-The-Sun" approach.

Jan 2006 – Nov 2006 DMV, New York, USA Oracle Database Administrator / Programmer Analyst

Project: Accident Information System (AIS)

This project incorporates the new web technology used for the tracking of accidents, recordings, processing, archiving, and overall clear and accurate operations, with recordings of alterations by the New York State Department of Motor Vehicle (DMV). The target audience for this is the personnel at Accident Records Bureau (ARB) at the DMV.

## Key Duties:

- Worked in Oracle 9i/10g databases and created views, functions and Stored Procedures.
- Determination / debugging worked with Application Development staff on problems.
- Oracle migrations, RAC and Oracle database daily maintenance.
- Enterprise Manager (Management packs) R&D, installation and operations.
- Analyzing and repairing chained rows.
- Check and purge log tables and files, check for tables in extents.
- Assist in planning and R&D on upgrade.
- Importing and exporting the xml files through FTP to and from external entities.
- Work flow (ODOC) management and error rectification.
- Backup and recovery using RMAN and traditional hot/cold backups.
- Wrote scripts for hot and cold backups.
- Involved in the Business Process Study and Technical Requirements.
- Used PL/SQL and UNIX based load scripts.
- Responsible for Query Optimization for improving the performance of the database.



## Dec 2003 – Dec 2005 Al Hamed Developments, Dubai, UAE Oracle Database Administrator

Project: Data warehouse Development, Maintenance & Support

The project is used to enhance and maintain an existing very large data warehouse which deals with the complete install base for the company. The warehouse is used for reporting the new and old quotes, service contracts and the entire install base for the customers. Reporting for the warehouse is done using Business Objects. There are various layers over the basic warehouse structures which provide the customized data to different downstream user community.

#### Key Duties:

- Requirement Analyze and recommendation for migration/upgrade of 9i to 10g.
- Patch analysis, recommendations and database coordination.
- Cloning and periodic purging of historic data.
- Responsible for enhancement of the system which includes addition of new schema mappings.
- Involved in Business Process Study and technical requirements for different enhancements.
- Extensively involved in Query Optimization for improving the performance of the database.
- Involved in the system restoration and verification process.
- Involved in the automation of different manual processes in the databases.
- Responsible for Metadata creation for Data Extraction, Transform and Load processes, PL/SQL scripts.
- Developed PL/SQL and UNIX Shell Scripts.
- Setup, installation and configuration of new databases.

Mar 2003 – Oct 2003 Human Base Inc., Bangalore, India Junior Oracle Database Administrator / Analyst

Project: Data warehousing Design, Order Management & DoCmatch System Development

The project was to design the Order Entry Data mart which is used for reporting the order status, returns order status versus reporting the productivity of the customer service team. The reporting for the warehouse is done using Business Objects. The Order Management System is developed in Visual Basic environment. The database for the entire GEA order management is based on Oracle. The Visual Basic environment talks to the database using the Remote Procedure calls and the ADO objects.

### **Key Duties:**

- Applied mandatory and conditionally required patches.
- Wrote scripts for hot and cold backups.
- Monitoring and tuning the database server performance.
- System Study, Design and Development.
- Used Business logic for the variety of orders.
- Responsible for Enhancement of the DoCmatch system.
- Involved in Business Process Study and Technical Requirements.
- · Responsible for Dimensional modeling of the DataMart.
- Shell and PL/SQL scripts and some data extracts were done using C programs.
- Responsible for Query Optimization for improving the performance of the data warehouse.
- Developed PL/SQL and UNIX Shell Scripts.
- Developed the scheduling scripts using the Maestro Job scheduler.
- Responsible for Multidimensional analysis, Business Objects structure.
- Created standard and adhoc database reports on demand.

## **EDUCATION & TRAINING:**

- Master of Computer Applications (MCA) VT University, Bangalore, India [Mar/2003]
- Bachelor of Computer Science (BSc. Computer Science) Mahatma Gandhi University, Kerala, India [Jan/2000]



## **DBA WORKSHOPS / COURSES:**

- Oracle Database 10g: Administration Workshop II Release 2 Training
- Oracle Database 11g: Administration Workshop II Release 2 Training
- Oracle Database 11g: Performance Tuning Ed II 2 Training
- Oracle Database 12c: New Features for Administrators Ed II Training
- Oracle Database 12c: Automatic Storage Management Administration Training
- Oracle Database 12c: RAC Administration Ed I
- Oracle Database 12c: Launch Seminar
- Oracle Database 12c: Upgrade Workshop
- Oracle Database 12c: In-Memory Database Extreme Performance in the Cloud Workshop
- Oracle Enterprise Manager Cloud Control 12c/13c: Install & Upgrade two day workshop
- ITIL(R) Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management Training
- Dynatrace Digital Performance & Application Performance Monitoring
- General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) workshop